Friends, HDFC Bank has taken such a
decision that its
impact will be visible on all the customers and friends, this
change, this decision has already been
implemented from yesterday's date, so what is this
decision due to which all the
customers are going to be impacted, I will
talk about it in full details in this video, please
watch the video completely and if you have
come to my channel for the first time, then definitely subscribe to the channel
and if you also have an
HDFC account, then definitely show this video, even if you do not have it,
please watch the video and definitely forward this video to anyone in your friends and family
who has an HDFC account, so
friends, let's
talk about the topic, brother, brother, banks set
a minimum interest rate
whenever they provide a loan, which means that the
bank will not give any loan below that rate, it is
called MCLR and rate or
you can call it operating rate, so
you will not get any loan below that rate and
friends, this rate
changes with time, especially RBI
which increases or decreases the repo rate.
It is directly linked with that and
we all know what the repo rate is,
for those who don't know, let me explain it to you,
in short, it is the repo rate and the rate at which
RBI
gives loan or money to the bank,
so if RBI also increases its interest rate, then the
bank also increases its interest rate,
so friends, in this way the entire
banking process is reduced and I would
like to tell you that recently, that is,
after two days, the RBI monitor
is the policy where a decision can be taken on whether the repo rate will increase or
decrease,
but friends, HDFC Bank has
taken a shocking decision, in yesterday's date,
which was the 7th date, it has been said there that the
MC rate, which is the minimum
interest rate, means that no loan will be available below that,
that rate has been increased by 15 basis points, which
means directly from now on, you will have to pay a
higher rate of interest for whatever loan you take, so its impact will be
that your EMI amount will also increase
and friends, this has become effective as of
yesterday's date  This means that from the 7th date, whatever loan
you take, this interest will be charged on it.
And friends, I would like to tell you that this increase in the interest
rate has happened only on short
term loans, that is, loans of one year or less.
And you also know that
mostly it will be applicable on personal loans or consumer goods of less than one year, which is home loan
etc. Or if there is any
personal loan in the long term, then there is not going to be much impact on it.
So friends, here I am
showing you on the screen, here
you can see the latest MC and rate. The
decision taken by HDFC to
increase the MC rate was
before the monetary policy of RBI. So what do you think, is it right
or wrong? And friends,
in the coming time, it is possible that all the other
banks may also increase their rate of interest.
So, what is your point of view
on this matter, you can definitely tell me.
Whatever information I have given you so far,
its official link can be found in the description of the video,
you can go there too.  You
can also read it from here. Friends, at the end of the video, I
would like to tell you one thing that if you
want to invest in the stock market, then
a demat account is required for that.
You also know that you can open a demat account for free, in
which there will be no joining fee
or annual maintenance fee.
Its link of Angel Wall
is in the description of the video, you
can open the account here and friends,
after opening the account, if you trade yourself
or refer someone else, then
there also you can get up to Rs 500 on
Amazon. Friends,
its link will also be found in the description of the video.
You can download it from there and
open your demat account. So
friends, we will meet in the next video. Till then, take
care of yourself. Jai
Hind Vande Mataram.